Previously on Billions.
I want to introduce the chairman of
the NYC 2028 Olympic Commission,
Michael Prince.
Thank you, Mayor Johnson.
You promised me a winning season, Chuck.
Running out of time
before I'll have to quit,
campaign 25/8.
I can't lose my MVP yet.
I need you, Kate.
Chuck Rhoades is fucking
with our Wi-Fi play.
The only winner in this
hopeless fucking outing
is gonna be your chief legal counsel.
You think I'm concerned because you
brought my Wi-Fi play back to Chuck?
It's how I know that you'll
serve me loyally as well,
until I help get you
elected to Congress.
You made a deal that you
knew would displease me.
I thought we could
actually change the world.
If you want to change the world,
nine digits ain't gonna do it.
How could you, Kate?
After all I taught you.
You made me wait.
What if the professor
isn't done teaching?
This is business.
This is what not having
a soft landing feels like.
You tear your butt when
you hit the ground.
Mike Prince and his daughters
made the world a better place today.
I lost my advantage.
I failed to protect my goddamn queen.
Welcome to Michael Prince Capital, Kate.
My God, let me finish!
When was I not letting you finish?
Worked pretty well in
Stand and Deliver too.
Life lesson,
always carry a cleaver.
Oh, wait. No.
That's not really the lesson.
The lesson is,
know how to change the
mood in a room quickly
and with authority.
Now, look,
I get what you're fighting over.
I do.
Coding team wants more of the budget
because you can't make a
great app without great code.
Sales team wants more because
who cares about the damn code...
You want to start moving
product out the door.
Same with the marketing group.
But here's the deal.
Your customer can have two of these,
not three.
Cheap and fast can't also be good.
Good and fast can't also be cheap.
So you can fight over turf,
or...
you can figure out a vision.
Let the budget sort itself out.
Or I can double it.
Everybody gets what they want,
and I get a word with
the teacher outside.
Not sure that's the right lesson.
Most important one:
"Money makes the rules."
I'm surprised an esteemed
charter school like this
hasn't hammered it into their heads.
Why scrap over capital
when you can raise it?
Group, we're gonna take five
while Mr. Prince makes out his check.
If you came here to impress a bunch of
teenage entrepreneurs...
Trying to impress you.
Hire you. How am I doing?
You opening a charter school?
Not for your side gig. Your main gig.
They take care of me at the fund I'm at.
Hmm-hmm. That's why
your resume's floating around.
In my weaker moments,
I sometimes think about
what I could do in a place
built for speed and power.
Then you're talking to the right guy.
Um,
what'd you do?
Nothing.
Women can be irrational, we know this.
"We" do not. What'd you do?
Not a thing.
I went unattended to a couples dinner.
Willow had a cold,
so Roxanne couldn't go.
And the distaff side of the other couple
was a fetching brunette...
Yeah, you had an affair.
Spare me the Penthouse Forum.
No-siree-Bob. Nothing physical.
Developed a kinship
with Judith Felker, Ron's wife,
over how thin the consommé was.
So uh, Roxanne kicked you out
over dinner table chatter?
Well, the next six days of
text chatter didn't help.
Did you know that Face ID
works when you're asleep?
Why wouldn't it?
You oughta go after Big Tech.
I dozed off mid-emoji,
Roxanne grabbed the damn
phone and saw it all.
I'll just drop this here
while I test the beds,
pick out a room.
_
The thing about self-help is,
if you're getting it from
someone else it's not self,
and if you're doing it yourself,
you didn't really get help.
Carlin.
George Carlin. No?
Yeah. All-time great.
But not quite like Coach Wooden.
See, he wasn't an entertainer.
He understood life.
Codified what he learned,
taught it to his basketball players,
made it available to the rest of us.
As I am now making it available to you.
"Initiative," "skill,"
it all seems kinda... basic.
Not ItsMeTinx basic.
Like what it used to mean.
I met him once, when we won State's.
Fundamental, not basic. It's different.
What'd he teach ya?
How to put on my socks and shoes.
How to lace 'em up and tie 'em right.
Know why?
Blisters?
To remember that every season,
we start again from the beginning.
We were champions of this season.
Not the next.
So we'd better do everything right.
Plus, yeah, blisters.
Not self-help.
Help.
- Who's that?
- Beats me.
Ten bucks says he doesn't
have any blisters.
Remember,
you're bowing to the Buddha, not me.
Yes.
Daniel.
I'm ready.
Is that the first sign of readiness,
do we think?
Stating it.
Are you suggesting I'm
not ready to take refuge?
Because I have to.
I need to.
What's that?
Vegan ice cream.
A gift for you. It's the best...
No.
What's that?
A gift for you, as I said.
I made it myself.
For what purpose?
For... to, uh...
To curry favor.
The very sweetness of the cream
is bitter in this way.
Do not buy friendship
or comfort.
Where I come from,
everything's a transaction.
Where you're going...
a commitment to the Buddha,
the Dharma, the Sangha,
the goal is to avoid being
transactional at all.
Can you do this?
Will you try?
I'll start with a month. Go from there.
Start with a day.
When I decide something...
Start with an hour, even a minute.
Then add a minute on to that one.
That's the work.
We'll meet again in four days,
see how it's going.
You're not sure I can
refrain from transacting
for four days?
Whether I'm sure matters not at all.
Well, I am.
I'm sure.
All right, rack the bid, get it done.
What's he, the new golden boy?
Took Dollar Bill's slot.
Probably looking for the
actual dollar to steal too.
Coach Wooden always said,
"I treat my players fairly,
but not equally.
Depends on performance."
And that's what we are evaluating now.
Performance.
Evaluate and decide who starts,
who rides the pine...
And who gets their scholarship pulled.
Now, I've always believed
you live in a house
before renovating,
so you don't sledgehammer
a support beam,
put a Barcalounger
where the bar should be.
Well, our grace period
here is coming to an end.
This Friday,
I'm reallocating capital at the firm.
If you change strategies,
if you stray from the fundamentals,
I'll see it, so don't.
Position sizing, focus, restraint...
consider them our load-bearing walls.
And, uh, oh, yeah, do your best.
For you.
To return to Coach Wooden,
"You're the only one who
knows whether you've won."
Pretty sure the guy carving
up our trading dollars
knows whether we've won.
Was he looking at me when he said
"Barcalounger?"
Quarter ends Friday.
If you fuck up, it'll be locked in,
and you'll be locked out.
What if you fuck up?
Then wake the hell up
from your nightmare
'cause in this life,
I don't ever fuck up.
I know you don't want me here.
Got that right.
Book a room at the Yale
Club for my father.
Mr. Allard needs you.
Have you decided who
gets Sacker's office yet?
Bureau chiefs have been eyeing it.
That's Graceland, we're not touching it.
Good. I need ya.
No, you need Marie Kondo.
Jesus Christ.
You got Aaron Burr's
gun permit lost in here?
But let me guess,
you know where everything is,
down to the last carbon.
Nope. Not a clue.
Where are we on the
prosecutions Sacker left behind?
Flailing, Chuck.
I have to admit,
I'm not as savvy on the legal stuff
as certain other aspects of the job.
Like this one.
Big seafood wholesaler.
Mislabeled half its product,
stuck people with cheaper fish instead.
The seafood fraud case,
we need a win on that.
To stand with the consumers
who're being fleeced.
Well, we may need
a different opposing counsel.
Lady's a pit bull, won't settle it out.
Even though we got her dead to rights.
I see that you did need me. Okay.
- I'll handle it.
- Good.
But that's not why I needed ya.
Last night,
in a private suite at the Garden,
a young woman walks up
to Governor Sweeney,
told him he's wrecking
the Empire State...
- Hmm.
- ...and not that nicely.
People heard it.
My sources tell me it was Gail Prince.
- Mike Prince's...
- Oh, I know who she is.
Governor Sweeney still doesn't.
Buffalo Bob finds that out,
he's gonna get ornery.
Page Six. Call over there and...
That I know how to do.
This'll be sweet.
As a Coolatta with extra syrup.
The Commission never
awards the Games to a place
it doesn't feel completely welcome in.
So...
This should pretty much lead to the end
of Mike Prince's Olympic bid.
Don't call my mom till I can explain...
Mom already got the call.
Let's get Kate Sacker in here.
First, I'd like to get
Philip Charyn out of here,
and understand how he even got in.